<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title></title>
	<link href="https://taehoon.dev/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
	<link href="https://taehoon.dev"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2020-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://taehoon.dev/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>First article - Zola is cool</title>
		<published>2020-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://taehoon.dev/blog/setup/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://taehoon.dev/blog/setup/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just started my own blog!&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It&#x27;s a first article and so let&#x27;s begin by writing whatever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me simply introduce what the tool I used for building this blog.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And my choice is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;getzola.org&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zola is A fast static site generator in a single binary with everything built-in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I decided what blogging platform to use, my requirements were these below:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown support&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s very natural to use WYSIWYG editors to write article, yeah, but...&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
At this point, I wanted to manage my blog contents using &lt;code&gt;git&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; but using WYSIWIG editors it can be quite tough.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
In usual cases, contents generated by WYSIWIG editors are not only that human-readable,
but also it is hard to replace an existing WYSIWIG editor to other one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting stuck at something, that&#x27;s something I&#x27;d really liked to avoid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Markdown can be a very proper choice.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It&#x27;s very portable and Markdown is also human-readable itself.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I don&#x27;t need to worry about this kind of scenario: what should I do when my blogging platform is shutdown or outdated..?&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Using Markdown, it&#x27;s quite easy to move to any other blogging platforms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Static site generator&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays &lt;em&gt;Web&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is not only for making something documents to read.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
We can now make almost whatever in web development environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for me, that was even the main source of my income for a last few years.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I made lots of complex websites and web based applications.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
But for blogging, that can be too much.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Static HTML is just enough for building something... website for &lt;em&gt;readings&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...blah blah blah...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I... just don&#x27;t want to take care about updating React version for running my blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written in Rust&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very simple reason, I like Rust, I love Rust
so if there exists static site generator written in Rust, why not using that?&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Maybe I can even contribute to the project in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that static site generator is written in PHP, though I choose that,
I will not ever consider to contribute to the project.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
But for Rust project, I can happily do something for free.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zola&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Zola satisfies all 3 requirements, so I chose it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
